# **Tommy Li**

Software Engineer

# **SUMMARY**

I enjoy the challenge of solving difficult problems, and I believe the best engineer thing like designers. Whether it's a user interface or an external API, I think about who will be using the things I built and make sure to provide a good user experience. Proven track record of creating and implementing successful front and back-end web applications.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Software Engineer at OSLabs

Aug 2022 — Present

- Collaborated with a team of developers on a full-stack application where we built an open source application for GraphQL developers
- Implemented a GraphQL IDE using Monaco Editor to allow users to test GraphQL queries, providing a one-stop testing and data-monitoring playground
- Leveraged TypeScript to improve application scalability and make debugging the codebase easier by eliminating type errors prior to runtime
- Integrated Apollo Server to an Express backend to communicate with PostgreSQL database for faster and strongly typed queries and mutations
- Deployed with Docker/AWS EB and setup Cloudfront distribution to direct all incoming traffic to the registered domain name as well as sending all outgoing requests using a secure HTTPS port

Product Developed: Kensa (GraphQL API Monitoring App)

Tech Used: TypeScript | React | Redux Toolkit | Node.js | Express.js | PostgreSQL | GraphQL | Apollo | Chakra UI | Git | AWS | Webpack | Monaco Editor

#### Software Engineer Toli Development

Jan 2018 — Present

Completed many projects for clients, including building custom full-stack applications and static websites, hosting, doing SEO work for the websites, and using tools like MailChimp to create marketing and handle mailing lists

#### **Recent Projects:**

tasksAl (Fullstack Mobile App) – Worked with a team of engineers to develop a task-organization app using React Native and Python/Flask backend that utilizes machine learning to help users boost productivity by generating metrics and recommendations

**MonoJStick (Fullstack Web App)** – JavaScript one-liner snippets sharing app built with React, Firebase authentication, and Firebase real-time database

# **SECONEA | Norwalk, CA**

June 2021 — Dec 2021

Handled a range of assignments that vary in scope and responsibilities, including utilizing various consultative methods to analyze client needs, ensuring quality in project delivery, and managing project budgets and schedules

# CONTACT

(415) 819-8043

tommylidev@gmail.com

ToLi Development

LINKEDIN

**GITHUB** 

#### **LANGUAGES**

Javascript

**TypeScript** 

SQL/Postgresql

Python

HTML/CSS/Sass

#### **SKILLS**

React / React Native

Express.js / Node.js

SQL (PostgreSQL)

NoSQL (MongoDB)

**AWS** 

Heroku / Netlify / Vercel

Webpack / Vite

Glt / Github

Flask / Django

Jest / Supertest

Authentication

# **CERTIFICATION**

**AWS Certified** 

**Cloud Practitioner** 

#### **EDUCATION**

Cal Poly,

San Luis Obispo

2016 - 2021

Bachelor's degree